[ Applause ]
[ 掌声 ]
&gt;&gt; Welcome.
&gt;&gt; 欢迎
We introduced the host of new
我们结合 Metal 2
technologies with Metal 2 to
推出了许多
allow you to make better,
新的技术 能让你们制作
faster, and more efficient
更好 更快
applications.
更有效率的应用
My name is Michal and together
我是 Michal
with my colleague Richard we'll
我和我的同事 Richard
explore three main themes today.
今天将给大家介绍三个主题
With Metal 2 we are continuing
通过使用 Metal2
our direction of moving the
我们将继续减少
expensive things to happen less
高代价操作的发生
frequently and making sure that
并确保
the frequent things are really,
常用的操作
really cheap.
只花费很少的代价
Over the years we introduced
历年来 我们介绍过
precompiled shaders, render
预编译着色器
state objects, Metal Heap last
渲染状态对象和去年的 Metal 堆
year all to make sure that you
以保证你能将
can move the costly operations
高代价的操作
outside of your main application
移除出你的
loop.
主要应用循环
We gave you 10 times more draw
通过将 open GL 换成 Metal
calls by switching from open GL
我们能给你提供 10 倍多的
to Metal.
绘图调用
And this year we are introducing
今年 我们将介绍
our new binding API that gives
新的绑定 API
you some more.
它能为你提供更多的功能
And so we will talk about it a
因此我们将
bit further.
进一步介绍它
We are also putting GPU more in
通过 GPU 驱动流水线
a driving seat with GPU driven
我们将进一步把 GPU 放在
pipelines.
驱动的位置
And you will be able to create
而通过在现代 GPU 上使用 Metal 2
new, novel algorithms, new
你将可以创造新的算法
rendering techniques, and whole
新的绘制技术
unique experiences utilizing
并获得完全独一无二的
Metal 2 on modern GPUs.
体验
Well, speaking of the
当然 说到体验
experiences, we have a lot of
我们在 Metal 里
new features in Metal and we
增加了很多新功能
have three other sessions that I
同时我们还有其他三个会议
would love you to attend.
我非常希望大家能参加
VR is coming to Mac this year
Mac 在今年迎来了 VR 技术
and with the new iMacs we are
通过新的 iMac  我们将
giving you really powerful GPUs.
为你提供非常强大的 GPU
The external GPU is coming to
即将登陆 MacBook Pro 的
MacBook Pro to give you the same
外部 GPU 也将给你同样
power.
强大的功能
And this all enables your users
这些都能让你的用户和
and your content creators to
你的内容创作者
experience VR in ways not
获得前所未有的
possible before.
VR 体验
Tomorrow's session will show you
明天的会议将向你展示
how to use our display -- direct
如何使用我们的
display technology -- to get
直接显示技术
your content to HMD quick and
来使你的内容快速并且
with low latency.
低延迟地到达 HMD
You'll learn about the new Metal
你将学到新的
API editions for VR and our new
为了 VR 制作的 Metal API 版和新的
Tools editions.
工具版
Machine learning is quickly
机器学习正非常迅速地
becoming a key feature of our
在很多应用中成为
devices in many, many
我们设备的
applications.
关键功能
And with Metal 2 you can use
你可以用通过 Metal 2
Metal performance shaders to
来使用 Metal 性能着色器
utilize the power of the GPU for
并利用 GPU 的能力
machine learning on both test up
在测试中和
and mobile devices.
移动设备上进行机器学习
And you're probably staring at
你可能正盯着
that picture behind me and
我身后的图片
thinking, "How's that done?"
在想 “这是怎么做到的？”
Well, we have a session for you
我们有一个会议
on Thursday where you will learn
将在周四举行
about this and about the machine
从中你能学到这个以及
learning primitives -- the image
机器学习原语
processing primitives -- we have
也就是我们的
in our Metal performance
Metal 性能着色器里面的
shaders.
图像处理原语
Lastly, our tools have seen the
最后 在 Metal 2 引擎下
biggest advancement yet with
我们的工具已经取得了
Metal 2.
重大的提升
You'll be able to debug your
你将可以快速的
applications quicker.
对你的应用进行故障排查
You can drill down to problems
你能更容易的发现问题
easier and we are exposing, for
我们还将曝光一些东西
example GPU performance
例如 GPU 性能计数器
counters, to make sure that you
以确保你能
can find your hotspots and your
找到你的热点
application fast pass quicker.
你的程序也将运行的更快
So I hope I got you excited
好了 我希望我已经使你们
about the few days ahead and
为未来几天感到兴奋
let's get back to the present
现在我们回到
with the content of today's
今天会议的
session.
内容
So we'll start with argument
我们将从参数缓冲器开始
buffers, probably our biggest
这也可能是我们今年
core framework addition this
在核心框架上增加的
year.
最重要的内容
argument buffers provide an
参数缓冲器能提供一个
efficient new way of configuring
全新的高效方式来
which buffers, textures, and
配置缓冲器 纹理和
samplers your application can
采样器  使你的应用能够使用
use freeing up considerable
被释放出来的
amount of CPU resources and
可观的 CPU 资源
actually enabling completely new
并能使 GPU
schedules for the GPU at the
真正同时运行
same time.
全新的计划
Then we'll talk about Raster
下面我们来谈谈光栅顺序组
Order Groups, a new fragment
一种新的片段着色器
shader synchronization primitive
同步原语
that allows you to precisely
它能让你
control the order in which
精确的控制
fragment shaders access common
片段着色器接入公共存储器的顺序
memory, enabling you new use
使得你能够使用
cases for example of
例如
programmable blending on MacOS
MacOS 上的可编程混合
or voxelization [phonetic] order
或者体素化
independent transparency.
顺序无关的半透明渲染
And then we'll switch to the
然后我们将话题转到
topic of display and we talk
显示上来  我们将谈到
about the new ProMotion Displays
iPad 上全新的 ProMotion 显示器
on iPads and how to best drive
以及如何使用 Metal
them using Metal.
去运行它
And we'll also give you a recap
我们也将简要重述
of our best practices of getting
如何用最快的速度
your content from your render
以及最少的延迟
targets to the glass as quickly
使你的内容
as possible and with the least
从渲染目标
amount of latency.
传递到眼镜上
And finally we'll finish with a
最后我们将以一个
survey of all the other Metal
关于所有其他
features that we added to align
被我们加入到 iOS 和 MacOS 平台里
iOS and macOS platforms into one
以配合 Metal 生态系统的 Metal 功能调查
big, common Metal ecosystem.
结束今天的会议
So the argument buffers.
好的 关于参数缓冲器
Let's look at what they are and
让我们来看看它们是什么
how they work.
以及它们如何运作的
And I will need an example for
我将需要举个例子
that so let's think of a simple
让我们想象一个简单的材料
material that those who actually
一个那些写过
wrote any sort of 3D render
3D 渲染程序的人
program would know.
都会明白的材料
In your material you have a
在你的材料里有
bunch of numerical constants, a
大量的数值常量
bunch of textures -- probably
大量的纹理
more than two now a days --
以及多于每天两个的
assembler.
汇编程序
And this is what you need to
而这就是你需要发送给
send to the GPU to be able to
GPU 来
render your primitive.
渲染你的原语的东西
Now the texture objects are
纹理对象很有趣
interesting because they contain
因为他们
both texture properties such as
不仅包含了纹理属性 例如
width, height, pixel format
宽 高 甚至还有像素格式
perhaps, and then a pointer to a
它同时还包含了一个
blob of memory which contains
容纳所有美丽像素的
all the pretty pixels.
内存的指针
Well, unfortunately we are not
不幸的是 我们今天的会议
really interested in those
对那些像素
pixels in this presentation.
不是很感兴趣
So off it goes and we'll only be
所以我们会放下它
talking about boring texture
而仅仅讨论乏味的
states.
纹理状态
So with traditional argument
传统的参数模型
model we allow you to put all
允许你将所有的
the constants into a Metal
常量放在 Metal 缓存器中
buffer and we created this
然后我们创建这个
indirection so that it's easy
间接方式 这样你能轻松的
for you to use and also it gives
使用它 同时它还可以
GPU the unfiltered, direct
在 GPU 未过滤的情况下
access to all the data.
直接接入所有的数据
However, when it comes to things
但是 当面对类似
like textures or samplers you
纹理或者采样器时
still need to go through quite
你还是需要
about of an API and in your
通过一个 API
rendering loop you'll set the
在你的渲染循环中
buffer, set all the textures,
设置缓存器 所有的纹理
samplers, and only after that
以及采样器 只有如此
you can finally draw.
你才能最终开始绘制工作
And even though Metal is really
即使 Metal 已经
optimized this is quite a few
被高度优化了 这里还是存在
API codes and if you multiply it
一小部分 API 代码
with the number of objects you
如果你将每一帧要渲染的对象数量
need to render, every frame, and
和它相乘
the fact that you need to do all
而事实上你确实需要
this work every frame, it
对每一帧都做这些工作
actually at some point limits
实际这在某种程度上限制了
the amount of objects that you
你能放在屏幕上的
can put on the screen.
对象数量
With argument buffers we decided
通过使用参数缓冲器
that we would like to extend
我们希望拓展
this very convenient indirection
这种对常量来说方便的间接取值
that we have for constants to
使它能应用于
everything.
所有的东西
So you can actually put texture
事实上你可以将纹理状态
state, samplers, pointers to
采样器以及指向另一个缓存器的指针
another buffer into an argument
都放入一个参数缓存器中
buffer and this really
这可以很大程度上
simplifies your rendering
简化你的渲染流水线
pipeline because -- well,
因为突然间
suddenly the only thing you need
你要做的唯一一件事
to do is set the buffer and
就是设置缓存器
draw.
然后绘制
And you probably figured out
你可能发现了
that with this few API calls you
因为更少的 API 调用
can put more objects on the
你可以在屏幕上放置更多对象了
screen, and as you'll see later,
正如你将看到的那样
you can do actually even better
事实上 你可以使用参数缓存器
with argument buffers.
做到更好
So we've done a bunch of
好了 我们已经做了很多
benchmarks and run argument
基准测试 并在
buffers on our devices.
我们的设备上运行了参数缓冲器
And this is for example what you
这是你将在 iPhone 7 上
get on iPhone 7.
看到的例子
While with traditional model,
使用传统的模型
quite unsurprisingly, the cost
一点都不令人惊讶
of your draw call scales, with
在你的绘制调用中
the amount of resources you use
用到的资源会很庞大
in a draw call, with argument
而使用参数缓存器
buffers the cost stays pretty
这个代价会很低
low and almost flat.
甚至没有
So this already shows that for
这已经证明了
example with a very simple
通过一个简单的着色器
shader, with just two resources,
两个资源
with texture and a buffer, or
以及纹理和一个缓存器
two textures, you're getting
或者两个纹理
seven times the performance
你将获得 7 倍的
improvement.
性能提升
With eight textures or eight
有 8 个纹理或者 8 个资源
resources, however you want to
如果你希望能
mix it up, you are getting 18
将他们混合起来
times performance improvement on
你将在 iPhone 7 上获得 18 倍的性能提升
iPhone 7 and it goes even better
显然 他能在16 个资源的时候
with 16 resources, obviously.
运行的更好
So I already talked about the
好了 性能方面
performance.
我就讲到这里
I hinted toward a new use -- new
接下来我将介绍一个新功能
use schedules.
新的使用计划
And we'll talk about this in a
我们稍后会
minute.
谈到它
And the last point -- the last
最后一个要点
benefit of argument buffers I
最后一个我想讲到的
would like to bring up is the
参数缓存器的好处
ease of use.
是使用的方便性
And it comes from the fact that
这是因为
argument buffers are ultimately
参数缓存器实际上
an extension of buffers.
是一个缓存器的扩展
So you can, for example go ahead
所以你能
and prepare them ahead of the
例如 提前把它准备好
time, let's say when your game
比如当你的游戏正在缓冲
is loading, and then don't have
而你不需要
to worry about it anymore during
在你的渲染循环时再担心它
your rendering loop, further
这将进一步
improving your performance.
提升你的性能
Or you can mix them with a
或者你可以将它们
traditional binding model, for
与一个传统的混合模型结合
example even within a single
比如在一个
draw call, which means that your
单一的绘制调用中
adoption can be as simple as
这意味着你可以简单的
using our new tools to figure
用我们的工具
out what is your most expensive
来判断哪些是你应用里
loop in our application and
代价最高的循环
optimizing that and then maybe
你可以优化它
return to the rest in a year
然后你可以在剩下的一年中处理余下的问题
when you have time.
在你有时间的时候
And lastly, the argument buffers
最后 参数缓存器
are supported across all Metal
支持所有的
devices.
Metal 设备
So once you take this adoption
所以 只要你使用了它
step and you get all the
你会拥有它所有的性能
performance you can keep using
你也可以在所有的 Metal 设备上
it on all Metal devices.
继续使用它
The ease of use actually
使用的方便性 事实上
translates really well to the
也很好的应用在了
shaders.
着色器上
And since we will be looking at
我们将在本次会议中
the shaders quite a bit during
谈到一点关于
this section -- this is an
着色器的内容
example of the material I gave
这是我在会议开始时给大家
you in the beginning.
提出的例子
And as you can see, the textures
你可以看到
in the sampler are part of the
采样器中的纹理是
structure, and that's the main
结构的一部分
thing to take away from this is
这也是你们要从这里学到的主要内容
that your argument buffer is
那就是参数缓存器
just a structure in a shader and
只是一个在着色器里的结构
you can use all the language
你可以使用处理器里的
that you have at your disposal
所有语言
to make embedded structures, to
去创造嵌入结构
organize your data, or use erase
去组织你的数据 使用删除
or pointers.
或者指针
It just really works.
它能运行的很好
So let's now look at the three
现在让我们看看
main new features of argument
参数缓存器的三个主要的新功能
buffers, the first one being
第一个就是
dynamic indexing.
动态索引
And great example of it is crowd
一个非常好的例子
rendering.
就是批量渲染
If you played some of the recent
如果你最近玩了
Open World games you've seen
一些开放世界游戏 你会看到
that games try to render large
这些游戏试图渲染
crowds full of unique, varying
大量特殊的
characters in order to make
不同角色 来创造一个
these beautiful, immersive
美丽的 拟真的
worlds.
世界
Well, actually that's quite a
事实上
costly thing to do if you need
如果你需要进行这么多绘制调用
to create so many draw calls.
是一件代价很高的事情
With argument buffers we already
我们提到过 使用参数缓存器
said that we could put all the
我们可以将所有的
properties required for let's
所需属性 比如
say a character into a single
一个人物
argument buffer, bind it, and
放入一个单独的参数缓存器  绑定它
save all that performance on the
这可以节省所有的 CPU 性能
CPU, but actually we can do
不过我们可以
better.
做的更好
We can for example create an
例如 我们可以
array of argument buffers where
创建一个参数缓存器队列
each element represents single
其中每个元素代表一个
character.
字符
And then it suddenly becomes
然后 这会变得非常简单
very, very simple because what
因为你需要做的
you need to do is set this big
就是设置这个大的缓存器
buffer, this one API call, issue
这是第一次的 API 调用
single instance draw call, let's
它可以处理单一的绘制调用实例
say with 1,000 instances because
比如说 1000 个实例
I would like 1,000 characters on
因为我希望有 1000 个人物
screen.
显示在屏幕上
That's second API call.
这是第二次 API 调用
And after that it's all on the
完成之后
GPU.
它就都在 GPU 上了
In a vertex shader you use
在顶点着色里
instance ID to pick the right
你可以用实例 ID 从队列中
element from the array, get the
选择正确的元素
character, put it somewhere
获得人物并将他
where it needs to be in the
放置在世界里需要他的地方
world, give it the right pose,
给他正确的姿势
if it's for example mid-walk
假如是步行周期中间
cycle, and then in the fragment
在片段着色器中
shader again you use the
你再一次使用
instance ID and pick the right
实例 ID 然后选择正确的材料
materials, the right hair color
正确的发色来
to finalize the look.
完成这个人物的外貌
So we are suddenly getting from
所以 我们能很快将
tens, hundreds, maybe thousands
成千上万的绘制调用
of draw calls to a single one.
变成单一的一次调用
And it's faster on the CPU.
而且它能在 CPU 中运行的更快
It's faster on the GPU.
在 GPU 中也更快
And this is how simple it looks
在着色中
in a shader.
它看上去就是如此简单
Pretty much your argument buffer
很大程度上你的参数缓存器
becomes an array of structures.
成为了一队列的结构
You pick the right element using
你可以使用内置的实例 ID
instance ID referenced within
来选择正确的元素
and you can, for example take
然后你可以 比如
the pointer and pass it to your
选择指针 然后将它传递给你的
helper methods or whatever you
辅助方法或者任何
need to do to process data.
处理数据所需的方法
The second great feature of
参数缓存器的第二个优秀功能
argument buffers is the ability
是 GPU 设置资源
of the GPU to set resources.
的能力
And we actually created an
事实上我们为它
example for this.
创造了一个例子
We created a particle simulation
我们创造了一个
running completely on the GPU.
完全在 GPU 上运行的粒子仿真
And I'll tell you how we done
让我来告诉你我们怎么做的
that and we'll see the -- we'll
我们将看到
see it in action later.
我们一会儿将看到它运行
So we created an array of
所以我们创建了一队
argument buffers where each
参数缓存器 他们中每一个
element is single particle --
元素是一个单个的粒子
and I guess you already spotted
我猜你已经看到了
a trend here.
这里的趋势
Our simulation kernel then
随后我们的仿真核将
treats and simulates one
每线程的对一个粒子进行仿真
particle per thread, but we want
但是我们想要
to actually go further and we
走得更远
want it to be able to create the
我们希望使 GPU
particles in the kernel as well,
在核心中
on the GPU.
也能创造粒子
So in order to do that, and to
所以 为了实现这个目标
give it the right materials, we
给予它正确的材料
also have argument buffer with
我们也有
all the different materials that
我们希望粒子拥有的
we would like our particles to
所有不同材质的
have.
参数缓存器
And our simulation kernel then,
我们的仿真核
every time you do an action in
每一次你想在样本里做一个动作时
our little demo, the simulation
这个仿真核就会
kernel looks into the
观察环境
environment and sees what's the
看看哪些是
correct, most appropriate
正确的 合适的
material.
材料
And let's say if you are in the
打个比方 如果你在
forest, we pick moss as the
一片森林里 我们选择苔藓
right, appropriate material for
作为一块岩石最正确合适的材料
a rock and copy it to the
然后将它复制到
particle itself.
粒子上
If you're on the rocks we pick
如果你在岩石上
the rock material.
我们选择岩石材料
On the hill we pick grass.
在山上我们选择草
So this way everything stays on
像这样 所有东西都在 GPU 上
the GPU and it actually looks in
它的着色真的就和
the shader just as simple as I
我描述的一样
describe it.
那么简单
If you want to modify data on
如果你想在你的 GPU 上
your GPU you bind it as a device
修改数据 你可以将它作为设备缓存器捆绑
buffer and start assigning
然后像你以前一样
values as you are used to, but
开始赋值
also this time around you can
但是这次你要
copy textures or copy the whole
复制纹理或者复制整个的
structure and it's really this
结构
simple.
这非常简单
And the last great feature I
我想介绍的
would like to mention is ability
最后一个参数缓存器的
of argument buffers to reference
优秀功能是
another argument buffer.
它可以引用另外一个参数缓存器
So this way you can actually go
这样你可以
ahead and create a reusable and
创建一个可重复使用的
complex object hierarchy just as
复杂对象层级
you are used to from C++ Swift,
就像 C++ Swift
Objective-C.
和 Objective-C 一样
Let's say in the example of our
打个比方 在我们的渲染器的例子中
renderer, if you have a ton of
如果你有大量的对象
objects, but you probably have
但你可能只有
very few materials, so what you
很少的材料 你可以做的是
can do is reference the material
从每个对象引用材料
from each object and save some
省下一些内存
memory or you can build your
或者你可以
scene graph as a binary tree
将布景图构建成二进制树形网络
where actually you point to the
在这里 当你需要时 你可以指向
objects and the tree nodes as
对象和树的节点
you need them, as you would be
就像你原来
used to from the CPU.
在 CPU 里使用一样
And you can share this data with
你也可以和 CPU 分享
the CPU as well.
这些数据
So these are the main features.
这些就是主要的功能
And let's look at the support
现在让我们来看看
matrix.
支持矩阵
We have two tiers.
我们有两个层级
The tier one is supported across
层级一是被所有
all Metal devices and you get
Metal 设备支持的
the CPU performance
你也可以提升 CPU
improvements.
的性能
You get the new schedule
你可以得到新的
language.
计划语言
But because of the limitations
但是因为 GPU 的限制
of the GPUs this tier does not
这个层级
-- is not able to utilize the
不能够像我之前提到的
GPU driven use cases that I
通过利用 GPU 驱动
mentioned earlier.
来使用用例
With tier two however you are
但是如果使用层级二
getting all of this -- so you
你可以得到所有的
get all the new use cases -- and
所有的新用例
we are also really increasing
我们也同样
the amount of resources you can
大幅提高了你能接入的
access.
资源
Your shaders can access half a
你的渲染器能接入
million textures and buffers to
50 万的纹理和缓存器
-- for you to do this -- do
让你能做这些
these new algorithms.
新的算法
While tier one is supported on
尽管层级一在所有设备上
all Metal devices, tier two is
都被支持  层级二是
something you need to query for.
你需要查询得到的
But don't worry, the support is
但是不用担心 这个支持
really wide.
非常广泛
All the Macs with these three
所有拥有这三个 GPU 的 Mac
GPUs are tier two.
都有层级二
All the new MacBook Pros, the
所有新的 MacBook Pro
latest MacBook, the last tier
最新的 MacBook 最后层级的 MacBook Pro
MacBooks Pros are tier two.
都有层级二
So you can go ahead and have
所以你大可以
fun.
玩得高兴
Now let's look at the demo I
现在 让我们来看看
promised you.
我承诺过给你们的样本
We will be showing three videos
我们将展示三个视频
with three different features.
其中包含三个不同功能
The real time rendered terrain,
这个被实时渲染的地形
with material that changes
有动态变化的材料
dynamically, we place some
我们利用 GPU 在地形上
vegetation by the GPU on the
放置一些植物
terrain to make it interesting,
来让它更有趣
and we have all these nice
我们也有这些我
particles that I mentioned
之前提到过的漂亮的
before.
粒子
So, as you see, we are painting
所以 就像你看到的
high on the terrain.
我们在地形上绘制高度
We can changing sculpting the
我们可以改变地表侵蚀
terrain and the material
随后材料也会
actually follows.
跟着变化
And this is a great thing about
这就是参数缓存器优秀的地方
argument buffers because they
因为它们
allowed us to create a one big
能让我们创建一个大的
argument buffer with all the
参数缓存器
possible materials as layers in
所有的可用材料和层级都在里面
there and when we are rendering
当我们在一个像素着色器中
the terrain in a pixel shader we
渲染地形时
are looking at things like
我们看到的是
terrain height, slope, the
地形的高度 坡度
amount of sun that reaches
有多少阳光到达特定的
certain pixels, and based on
像素 基于这些属性
these properties and some others
和其他属性
we do decide what are the best
我们能判断什么是用于
and most appropriate materials
这个像素上的最好的
for that given pixel.
和最适合的材料
And this is all happening in
这些都是
real time, whereas previously we
实时发生的  在以前我们可能需要
would have to go ahead and split
在线下
the terrain in small pieces
将地形拆成小块
offline, analyze which pieces
分析哪些小块
need which textures in order to
需要哪些纹理
make it as optimal as possible,
以使它最优化
and only then render it.
然后才能渲染它
So we are going from a
所以我们将一个
pre-processing step, which is
预处理的步骤
heavy and prevents real time
一个繁重的非实时的
modification, to something that
修改操作 变成了一个
is real time, without -- sorry
实时的 抱歉
-- without preprocessing and
不需要处理的
completely dynamic.
完全动态的步骤
And we added vegetation on it
我们在上面加上植被
and as you see the vegetation is
你可以看到植被
also context sensitive.
也是环境敏感的
You see the palm trees on the
你看沙滩上的
sand.
棕榈树
You see the little tiny apple
你看山丘上
trees on the hills.
小小的苹果树
And while the vegetation itself
植被本身还是一个
is fairly traditional instance
非常传统的实例渲染
rendering, the power of the
参数缓存器在这里
argument buffers here is that it
能做到的是
allows us to share the same
它使我们能将
terrain material with all the
所有的相同属性
same properties and the same
分享给同样的地形材料
terrain analysis function
并在完全分离的
between two completely separate
代码中间进行
pieces of code.
同样的地形分析功能
While terrain rendering uses all
当地形渲染器用
this data to render pixels, the
所有这些数据去渲染像素时
computer that places the
放置几何形状
geometry, the vegetation,
和植被的电脑
actually analyzes the same
事实上分析了相同的
materials to figure out what is
材料以判断
the best type of tree to place
最合适放置在指定地点上的
in the given spot.
是哪一种树
And this is very easy because
这非常简单因为
every time we make a change
每次我们在做改变的时候
nothing actually changes in our
我们的代码事实上没有任何变化
code because we just add new
我们只是增加了新的
layers or change our analysis
层级或者改变了我们的分析
function, whereas previously we
功能  可能从前我们需要
would have to maybe juggle 70
在两个完全分离的
textures between two completely
代码中间处理大概 70 个纹理
separate code basis in order to
以使他们能
make them run in sync.
同步的运行
Lastly, we have the particles.
最后 我们有粒子
I hope you can see that they
我希望你们注意到
nicely get the material of the
他们已经找到了
terrain there.
地形的材料
Now what I did not mention is
我之前没有提到的是
that this all is rendered with
这些全都是被
again a single draw call.
单个的绘制调用渲染的
We are rendering 16,000
我们这里使用单个的绘制调用
particles here with single draw
渲染了 16000 个粒子
call, with absolutely no
这个过程中完全没有
involvement on the CPU.
CPU 的参与
And not only do particles have
而且粒子不只是有
unique materials, they actually
特殊的材料 它们事实上
have unique shapes because
还有特殊的形状 因为
argument buffers allow --
参数缓存器
actually allow you to change
允许你在每个
your vertex buffer per draw
绘制调用里
call.
改变你的顶点缓存
This is something where if you
如果你试着不用
try to do that without argument
参数缓存器去处理它
buffers, we had to create a
我们需要创建一个
complicated control hand over
复杂的控件
between GPU that simulates and
在负责模仿的 GPU 和
the CPU that tries to come up
试图得到最佳
with the best set of draw calls
绘制调用组的 CPU 之间
to represent all this variety.
来代表所有的这些变量
So with argument buffers this
有了参数缓存器
became just very, very simple.
这将变得非常非常简单
Okay, so enough pretty pictures.
好了 看够了美丽的图片
And let's wrap my portion of the
让我们以一些
session with a look at some APIs
API 和一些实践例子
and some best practices.
来结束我的部分
As I mentioned before, argument
就像我提到的那样
buffers are an extension of
参数缓存器是 Metal 缓存器的
Metal buffers and that means all
延伸 这意味着
of our API related to buffers
所有与缓存器有关的 API
just works.
都能运行
You can go ahead and take
你可以找一个
argument buffer, copy it
参数缓存器 将它复制到
somewhere else; you can blitz it
别的地方 你可以将它
between CPU and GPU.
放到 CPU 和 GPU 中间
And while argument buffers look
尽管参数缓存器
like structures on the GPU for
看起来像渲染器在 GPU 里的结构
shaders, on the CPU you will use
在 CPU 里你将用到
MTLArgumentEncoder objects to
MTLArgumentEncoder 对象去
fill up the content.
填充内容
This abstraction allows Metal to
这样的抽象能让 Metal
create the most optimal memory
为任何
representation for any given
实际运行的特定 GPU 上的
argument buffer on that specific
指定参数缓存器
GPU that you are actually
创建一个最优化的
running.
内存表征
So you get the best performance.
这样你就可以得到最好的性能
It also frees you, as the
作为一个研发者
developer, from all these
它同时也将把你
details and worries about, for
从焦虑的细节中解放出来
example how each GPU represents
例如 每个 GPU 如何体现
what the texture is.
什么是纹理
Where does it live in memory?
它在存储器中应该放在什么位置
All of this changes from
所有这些从平台到平台的变化
platform to platform and we hide
我们将它们隐藏在
it between a simple interface so
简单的界面之间
that you can write very simple
这样你就可以写出非常简单的
and effective applications.
有效率的应用了
So I hope you're not worried
希望你们没有
about the encoder that I
为了我前面提到的
mentioned.
编码器感到发愁
It's really, really simple to
它真的用起来非常非常
use.
简单
For example, if you want to
举个例子 如果你想要
create an argument encoder for
为这个参数缓存器创建一个 参数编码器
this argument buffer all you
你只需要
need to do is get your Metal
让你的 Metal 使用
function that uses the argument
参数缓存器功能
buffer and ask the Metal
然后让 Metal 功能
function for the encoder and
调用编码器
that's about this.
就行了
This is all you needed to do.
这就是你要做的全部了
You get an object and you start
你得到一个对象 你开始
using a familiar set texture or
使用一个熟悉的纹理
filling constant API that is
或者像你在
very, very similar to how you've
Metal 里使用
been using Metal with command
命令编码器一样
encoder.
去填满 API
So this also plays into what I
这对我提到过的
said about ease of use and
过渡和使用的便捷性
transition.
也有效
There are multiple other ways of
还有很多创建编码器的
creating the encoder.
方法
You can go more explicit with
你可以使描述符
the descriptor, but that's
更精确 但是
something you should look into
如果你需要的话
in documentation if you need
你可能要去查找
such thing.
参考资料
We advise you to actually go and
我们建议你
get argument encoders from the
直接从着色器里获得
shaders.
参数编码器
Now with all those interactions,
现在 有了这些交互
GPU being able to step in and
GPU 可以介入
modify the argument buffers or
修改参数缓存器
you know dynamic indexing and
或者动态的索引
half a million textures, all
以及 50 万个纹理 如果这些全部混合起来
that in a mix, it's not really
Metal 不太可能
possible for Metal to figure out
去分辨
what -- for example what
例如在渲染的时候
textures or buffers do actually
应该使用
intend to use in your rendering,
哪些纹理和缓存器
but luckily you as a developer
但幸运的是 作为一个开发者
have pretty good idea about
你对此有
that.
很好的解决方法
So we ask you with argument
所以我们要求你
buffers to be quite explicit
对参数缓存器
about it.
尽量的熟悉
If you are using Heaps, and
如果你在使用堆
absolutely you should use Heaps
当然你需要使用堆
to get the best performance out
在你的平台上获得
of your platform and the best
最佳的性能
way of organizing your data, the
以及组织数据的最佳方式
only thing you need to do is
你唯一要做的事
tell Metal that you intend to
就是告诉 Metal 你想要用一个堆
use a Heap , or multiple Heaps,
或者多个堆
it's up to you.
这由你来决定
And -- this is -- this makes
这保证了
sure that the textures are
在渲染循环中
available for you in the
纹理是
rendering loop.
可用的
If you want to do something more
如果你想做到更具体
specific, let's say you would
比如你想要
like to write to a render target
从一个内部的着色器
from inside a shader, or you
写入渲染目标 或者你
would like to read from a dev
想从一个 dev 缓存器进行读取
buffer, you use a more specific
你可以使用一个更加具体的 API
API and tell Metal that you
然后告诉 Metal
intend to change resource and --
你想要用
with a specific way.
特殊的方式改变资源
And again, it's as simple as
再一次的
this.
就是这样简单
You don't need to do anything
任何其他的事
else.
你都不用做
So let's start out with a couple
让我们开始讲讲
of best practices.
几个最佳的实践例子
I think if you know Metal they
我想如果你了解 Metal
are very, very similar to what
它和我们向你介绍的
we are telling you about using
Metal 缓存器
Metal buffers.
十分相似
The best way to organize your
组织你的数据的最佳
data is by usage pattern.
方式是用 使用模式
And you probably have a ton of
你可能有很多属性
properties that do not change
它们不会随着
per frame.
每个帧进行变化
So put them into an argument
所以 将它们放入
buffer and share it with all the
参数缓存器 将它和所有的
objects so you will save memory
对象共享
this way.
这样你将节省内存
The same -- on the same -- on
同样的 另一方面
the other hand you will probably
你可能有很多
have a lot of properties that
属性 它们也确实随着每个
actually do change for every
对象进行变化
object and you need to manage
你需要在每一帧下
them every frame.
对它们进行管理
And for these I think the best
对于这个问题 我认为
way is to put those into
最好的方式是
separate argument buffers so
将它们发给不同的参数缓存器
that you can double buffer it or
这样你可对它进行双重缓存
whatever is your management
或者对任何你的管理计划
scheme and you don't need to do
进行两次运行 你不用
all the other copies to keep all
通过其他的复制
the data in there.
来使所有的数据存在里面
And then you will likely have a
然后你会有
ton of argument buffers that
一些完全不会
just don't change at all.
改变的参数缓存器
Let's say the materials, or
比如材料 或者
maybe some other properties, and
一些其他的属性
for these just create them at
对于它们 你可以
the initialization of your
在应用的初始化里创建它们
application and keep using them.
然后继续应用它们
Similar to Metal buffers, think
和 Metal 缓存器相似
about your data locality and how
想想你的数据位置 以及
you actually use your argument
你将如何使用
buffers.
你的参数缓存器
If, for example you have three
假如你有
textures that are accessed in a
3 个纹理 接入了着色器
shader, one after another, then
一个接一个
the best thing you can do is
这时你能做的最好的事就是
actually put those textures
在参数缓存器里将这些
close to each other in argument
纹理放置在相距很近的地方
buffers so that you maximize the
这样你才能最大化
use of GPU caches.
GPU 的缓存
And as I mentioned at the
就像我在会议开始时提到的
beginning, traditional argument
传统的参数模型
model is not going anywhere and
不能运用到每个地方
you should take advantage of it
你要合理使用它
and mix it with the argument
并且在能使情况更方便的时候
buffers whenever it's more
将它和参数缓存器
convenient.
混合使用
So let's say if you need to
比方说你需要对
change a single texture for
改变每个对象的单个纹理
every object, for example a cube
比如一个立方体的倒影
reflection, it probably would be
只为这个创建一个
an overhead to create argument
参数缓存器然后
buffer just for that and upload
每一帧都上载它 可能是一个
it every frame.
系统开销
So just use the traditional
所以 在这里我们
model for this.
使用传统的模型
That's it about argument
这就是
buffers.
关于参数缓存器的内容
I really hope you will adopt our
我真诚的希望大家能使用
new API and get some creative
我们的新 API 并创新性的
use cases out of it.
使用它
And please welcome Richard, who
请大家欢迎 Richard
will talk about the Raster Order
他将为大家介绍
Groups.
光栅顺序组
[ Applause ]
[ 掌声 ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you.
&gt;&gt; 谢谢
Hello. So thank you Michal.
大家好 谢谢你 Michal
So I'm going to take you through
我将带领大家度过
the rest of the day's
下面的展示时间
presentation, starting with
让我们从
Raster Order Groups.
光栅顺序组开始
So this is a new feature that
这是个新的功能
gives you control over the GPU's
它能让你控制 GPU 的
thread scheduling to run
线性调度
fragment shooter threads, in
以有序的运行
order.
片段射击线
This allows overlapping fragment
这让重叠的片段射击线
shooter threads to communicate
能够通过存储器进行沟通
through memory, where before it
在这之前
wasn't always really possible to
大多数情况下
do in most cases.
是实现不了的
So this opens up a whole new set
所以 这开启了一个
of graphics algorithms that were
全新的图像算法
not practically achievable with
如果只写入了对你的
just write only access to your
帧缓存器的接口或者
frame buffers or onward access
接入设备存储器
memory to device memory.
这是很难实现的
For example, one of our key --
举个例子
one of the key applications for
我们的关键应用中的一个
this is Order-independent
是顺序无关的
transparency.
透明渲染
We've been -- already talked a
我们今天已经谈了很多
lot today about how to reduce
如何降低你的 Metal 应用
the CP usage of your Metal
的 CPU 使用量的问题
application and this feature
这个功能
lets you build or an algorithm
让你创建一个算法
to include blending back to
以实现前后颠倒的混合
front without having to pay the
而不用为
CPU cost of triangle level
三角水平筛选
sorting.
而消耗 CPU
There's also been lots of
这里有很多针对
investigations into advanced
类似
techniques such as dual layer
双层的 G-buffer
G-buffers, which can
的先进技术的研究
substantially improve post
这种缓存器能
processing results, or using the
极大的提升 后处理结果 或者用
GPU rasterizer to sort of
GPU 的光栅器
voxelize triangle meshes.
来像素化三角形网格
For both of these onward
对于这些存储器
accesses to memory has been a
的前端接口
really large barrier to
在他们通往高效应用的路上
efficient implementations.
还有很大的阻碍
But probably the simplest and
可能对于这个功能而言
most common application for this
最简单最通俗的应用
feature is just implementing
是执行
custom blend equations.
定制混合方程
iOS hardware could always do
iOS 的硬件能很自然的
this pretty natively, but this
支持这样做
is not something that desktop
但是
hardware has traditionally been
这不是传统的台式机
able to do.
的硬件能够做到的
So I'm going to use custom
所以我们将定制混合
blending as an example
作为一个范例应用
application to introduce this
来介绍
feature.
这个功能
Okay, so pretty typical case of
三角混合的经典例子
triangle blending; one triangle
是一个三角在
over another.
另一个之上
Pretty much all modern GPU APIs
几乎所有现代的 GPU API
guarantee that blending happens
都能保证在绘制调用命令中
in draw call order.
可以进行混合
It provides this nice,
它能证明
convenient illusion of serial
这个简便的
execution.
串行执行的假想
But of course what's really
但是 事实上在幕后
going on behind the scenes is
发生的事是
GPU hardware's highly parallel.
GPU 硬件是高度并行的
It's going to be running
它将
multiple threads concurrently.
同时运行多个线程
And only this fixed-function
只有这个固定功能的
blend step at the end is going
混合步骤最后能
to be delayed until everything
延迟到所有东西
gets put back in order again.
都重新有序排列之后
There's this implicit wait that
在混合步骤之前
happens before that blend step.
有一个隐式等待
Things change however if the
事情可能会随着顺序改变
ordering -- if we need to put
如果我们不是需要在
things in order not at the end
片段射击的最后
of our fragment shooter, but
将事情排序 而是
right in the middle because in
在正中间 因为如果这样
this case triangle one wants to
三角一号想要在存储器里
write something to memory that
写东西 三角二号
triangle two's threads want to
可以进行
read from.
读取
If we want triangle two to be
如果我们希望三角二号
able to build upon and consume
能够在其上增加 以及
triangle one's data we need to
自定义三角一号的数据
get that ordering back.
我们需要回到那个排序
And so that's pretty much what
这基本上就是
Raster Order Groups provides.
光栅顺序组可以提供的功能
So I'm going to jump over to a
现在我要讲到
shader code example.
着色器代码的例子
So if I want to implement custom
如果我想要执行
blending, an initial attempt
自定义的混合 一个无效
that does not work is going to
初期的尝试
be to replace my classic
将会替换我经典的
graphics frame buffer with a
图像帧缓存器
read to write texture and
为一个读写纹理
perform all of my rendering and
它会直接对这个纹理
blending directly to this
执行渲染
texture.
和混合
But of course if the threads
当然如果我混合的线程
that I'm blending over have yet
还没有执行
to execute, or concurrently
或者正在执行
executing, this is -- this whole
这整个
remodify/write sequence is going
修改编写顺序
to create a race condition.
会创建一个竞争条件
So how do we use Raster Order
所以我们如何使用光栅顺序组
Groups to fix this?
去修复它呢
It's really, really easy.
这非常非常简单
All I have to do is add a new
我要做的就是
attribute to the memory that has
在有冲突访问的存储器上
conflicting accesses.
添加一个新的属性
At this point the compiler and
这时 编译程序和硬件
the hardware are going to
会开始
cooperate to be able to
合作
implicitly take the entire range
使整个一系列的着色器
of [inaudible] shader that
接入存储器
accesses that memory from the
从一开始
very first to the very last
到最后全部接入
access and turn it into a
然后在屏幕后面将它
critical section behind the
转变成一个
scenes.
临界区
You can also apply this
你也可以将
attribute to normal device
这个属性应用于普通的
memory pointers, not just
设备存储器指针上
textures.
而不仅仅在纹理上
So with that we get the thread
所以通过这样做 我们得到了
schedule that we want.
我们想要的线性调度
Thread one will proceed and
线程一将继续运行
write to memory and thread two
和写入内存 而线程二号
is going to stop and wait until
将停止 直到
thread one's write's complete
线程一的写入完成
giving us basically race free
并给我们一个对
access to this memory.
存储器的几乎无冲突接入
Oh, there's one other really
有一个
important topic and that's
非常重要的话题
talking about which threads are
线程是
synchronizing with each other.
相互同步的
So of course GPU hardware's
当然 GPU 硬件
going to be running not just
将要运行不止两个
two, but tens of thousands of
而是同时运行
threads at the same time and in
成千上万个线程
fact it's probably executing
事实上它可能
every single thread from both of
从这些三角中
these triangles simultaneously.
同时运行
So of all of these thousands --
所以 所有这些成千上万的
tens of thousands -- of threads,
线程
which one synchronizes with each
哪个是彼此
other?
同步的
So I've highlighted one pixel
我在这里高亮了像素
here because that's the answer
因为这是这个问题的
to this question.
答案
You -- this feature only
你 这个功能
synchronizes against other
只能和其他线程同步
threads that your current
即那些当下与你的
fragment shooter thread overlaps
片段射击线程重叠的
with, those other threads that
那些线程
are targeting the same frame
对准同样的帧缓存的
buffer xy location, targeting
xy 位置的线程  对准同样的
the same multi-sample location,
多样本的位置的线程
targeting the same render target
对准同样的
index.
渲染目标指数的线程
If I wanted -- and it
如果我希望
specifically does not provide
它没有具体提供
any guarantees at all against --
任何的保证
that you can safely access
让你能安全的
memory that are written by any
由相邻像素写入的
neighboring pixels.
内存
If you do need to have these
如果你的确需要这样的
kind of area -- or region of
区域或者影响区域
influence -- kind of algorithms
这样的算法
then you will need to go back to
你就需要回去使用
using full memory barriers
绘制调用之间的完整内存屏障
between draw call -- or full API
或者绘制调用或
barriers between draw calls or
渲染通道之间的
render passes.
完整 API 屏障
But this comes at a much higher
但是这会导致更加高的性能代价
performance cost and it does not
它也不能在
work in the case where you have
你的三角与单个的
triangle overlap within a single
绘制调用重叠时
draw call.
使用
But for these common algorithms
但是对于这些常用算法
that you do have only need
你只需要重叠
overlap only synchronization,
只需要同步
Raster Order Groups can get the
光栅顺序组能在
job done at a substantially
大幅减少性能代价的情况下
lower performance cost.
完成任务
So this is a pretty actually
这是很简单的
easy one and that's really all
对于这个问题  这真的是
I've got to say about it.
我要说的全部了
Raster Order Groups lets you
光栅顺序组让你
efficiently wait for overlapping
高效的等待重叠
and only overlapping threads to
并且只让重叠的线程来
finish their access to memory,
结束它们对存储器的访问
which enables a collection of GP
这能让
algorithms that were previously
之前的一部分
just too inefficient to use
太没有效率的 GPU 算法
practically in GPU hardware.
在 GPU 硬件上被很好的使用
This middle of shader thread
着色器中间线程的
summarization is a feature of
总结是最新的
the latest GPU hardware, so it
GPU 硬件的功能
is something you do need to
你真的需要运行它来
check for at run time.
试试看
In particular it's supported on
特别的是
the newest AMD Vega GPUs
它被最新的 这一周刚发布的
announced this week as well as
AMD Vega GPU 支持 并且
the past couple years' worth of
也被过去几年的 Intel GPU
Intel GPUs.
所支持
And that brings us on to our
这就要提到
second feature and that is the
第二个功能 那就是
new iPad Pro's ProMotion
新的 iPad Pro 的 ProMotion
Display.
显示器
So ProMotion, this is a
ProMotion 对
particularly great feature for
图形和游戏开发者来说
graphics and game developers and
是一个很优秀的功能
so I really want to show you
我非常想向大家展示
what you can do with it.
我能用它干什么
This is the first of a sequence
这是第一个序列
of timeline diagrams I'm going
的时间线图
to show you, showing us when the
我将向你们展示
GPU starts and finishes
它展示了当 GPU 开始和结束
producing a frame, and then when
制作帧 以及当
that same frame finally gets
同样的帧
onto the glass for the user to
最终到达眼镜 使用户能够看到
see.
的时间
The first and most obvious thing
ProMotion 做的第一件也是最明显的事
that ProMotion does is we can
是使我们现在能
now render at 120 frames per
以每秒 120 帧
second.
进行渲染
This feels absolutely fantastic
这对任何要求
for anything that has really
高速动画制作的东西
high speed animations, for
对任何要求
anything that's latency critical
严苛延迟的东西
such as tracking user touch or
例如对用户触摸的追踪或者铅笔输入
pencil input.
都非常好用
And it does have some catches.
它确实有很多抓取
You of course only get half as
对于每个帧 你当然只有
much CPU and GPU time available
一半的 CPU 和 GPU 时间能够用
per frame so you really have to
所以你需要
pay a lot of attention to
花很多精力去
optimization and it does
优化它
increase overall system power
这也会增加整个系统的
consumption.
能量消耗
But if you've got the right
但是如果你得到了正确的内容
content, where this matters, it
在它起作用的地方
gets a really payoff for the
它会回报在
user experience.
用户体验上
But ProMotion goes a lot farther
但是 ProMotion 做到的
than 120 frames per second
每秒渲染 120 帧
rendering.
还要多
It also provides much more
它同样为
flexibility regarding when to
何时调换下一个图像到眼镜上
swap the next image onto the
提供更多的
glass.
灵活性
We're not limited to just 120 or
我们没有限制 每秒渲染 120 帧
30 or 60 frames per second.
30 帧或者 60 帧
ProMotion behaves much more
当你的应用执行
gracefully as your application's
上下移动时
performance moves up and down
相比于
compared to a fixed frame rate
固定帧率的显示器
display.
ProMotion 表现的更好
For example, here I have a
举个例子 我这里有
timeline diagram of a title
一个时间线图 它有点
that, you know just -- is just
你懂的
doing too much GPU work to
只是为了
target 60 frames per second.
达到每秒 60 帧消耗了太多 GPU
You know they're producing
你知道他们
frames every about 21
每 21 毫秒制作一个帧
milliseconds or about 48 frames
或者说 1 秒制作
per second.
48 帧
The GPU is perfectly happy to do
GPU 很乐意这样做
that, but on the display side we
但是在显示器这一边
can only refresh once every 16
我们只能每 16 毫秒刷新一次
milliseconds and so we end up
最后我们只能得到
with this beating pattern.
一个跳跃模式
There's this stuttering that the
这种不顺畅就使得
user feels where some frames are
用户在眼镜上感觉到
on the glass a lot longer than
有些帧
others.
比其他的要慢得多
And it's not nice at all.
这一点也不好
And so pretty much universally
基本上全世界
what applications do in this
在这种情况下通用的做法
case is they all have to
就是
artificially constrain the frame
人为的将帧率
rate all the way down to 30
降低到
frames per second.
每秒 30 帧
They're basically trading away
他们基本上是
their peak frame rate in order
将峰顶的帧率交换出去
to get some level of
以换得一定程度的
consistency.
连续性
ProMotion does much better here.
ProMotion 在这里做的好很多
So if I just take the same
如果我用
application, move it to a
相同的应用
ProMotion display, it does this
将它移动到一个 ProMotion 显示器上
to our timeline.
它会对我们的时间线造成这样的影响
We now have a refresh point
现在 我们
every four milliseconds rather
每 4 毫秒有了一个刷新点
than every 16.
而不是每 16 毫秒
Our timeline gets pulled in,
我们赚得了时间
even with the GPU doing exactly
尽管 GPU 做着
the same work as before.
和以前一样的工作
The display can now present at
现在这个显示器
an entirely consistent 48 frames
持续的
per second.
每秒显示 48 帧
The user is now getting both the
用户现在既能
best possible frame rate and
有最好的帧率
perfect consistency from frame
又能体验最佳的
to frame.
持续性
This tradeoff that we had to
我们以前做的交换
make is completely gone.
已经完全不需要了
Furthermore -- so a second
此外 第二个例子是
example is that this time in
这次 应用想要
application that wanted to make
制作每秒 60 帧
60 frames per second, but one
但是一帧运行的时间
frame just ran a bit long and we
稍微久了一点
missed our deadline.
我们做过了最后期限
On a fixed frame rate display we
在一个固定帧率的显示器上
end up on the display side with
在显示器这一边
a pattern that looks very
我们可能会运用
similar to what we saw before.
与之前看到的相同的模式
ProMotion can fix this too.
ProMotion 同样可以修复这个问题
So frame one's time on the
一号帧一旦在眼镜上
glass, rather than it being
它将不会
extended by 16 milliseconds, is
被扩展到 16 毫秒
now only extended by four.
而只是现在的 4 毫秒
The degree of stutter that the
用户感觉到的断断续续
user experiences is tremendously
会被极大程度的减少
reduced and then frame two and
二号帧和三号帧
three, their latency gets pulled
他们的延迟被
right back into where they were
拉回到
before.
之前到位置
The system recovers right back
系统立刻
onto the timeline right away,
回到时间线上
latency is improved, and your
延迟被提高
application can proceed on.
你的应用可以继续执行了
We've just gotten right back to
我们正好回到了
where we wanted to be.
我们希望到达的位置
So put it all together, it just
所以总结起来
makes animation just feel that
它将动画变得
much more robust and solid no
更坚定 更稳固
matter what's going on.
无论发生什么
So how do you actually go about
那么你到底该
taking advantage of this?
如何运用这些优势呢
For normal UIKit animation, such
对于一般的 UIKit 动画而言
as scrolling through lists or
例如 滚动观看目录或者视图
views, iOS will do this entirely
iOS 将完全以新的方式
for you out of the box.
来完成
It will render it 120 frames per
它将在适合的时候
second when appropriate.
每秒渲染 120 帧
It will use the flexible display
它也将在适合的时候
times when appropriate.
运用灵活的显示时间
Metal applications though tend
Metal 应用
to be much more aware of their
对时间更加敏感
timing and so for those we've
所以对我们已经完成的功能
made this an opt in feature.
这是一个功能的选择
Opting in is done really easily
这个选择非常简单
just by adding a new entry to
你只需要在 bundle 目录下
your application bundles
的 info.plist 里添加一个
info.plist.
新的入口
Once you do this the timing
一旦你做了这个计时的行为
behavior of our three Metal
我们的三个 Metal 显示的
presentation API changes a
API 会出现
little bit.
小的变化
And so I'm going to walk you
我将为你们
through those three APIs and how
介绍这三个 API 以及
they change now.
他们如何改变的
So the first of our Metal
我们的第一个
presentation APIs is just
Metal 展示 API
present.
正在进行
It's -- it says present
它即将
immediately; schedule my image
在 GPU 结束之后的下一个
to be put on the glass at the
可以使用的刷新点上
very next available refresh
把我的图像
point after the GPU finishes.
显示在眼镜上
On fixed frame rate hardware
在固定帧率的硬件上
that's 16 milliseconds and on
这是 16 毫秒
iPad Pro that's now four
在 iPad Pro 上
milliseconds.
现在是 4 毫秒
This is the easiest API to use
这是使用最简单的 API
because it takes no runs.
因为它不需要运行
So it's the API that most of the
因此它也是在这个房间里的
people in this room are already
大部分人都在使用的
using.
API
It's also the API that gives you
这也是让你以
the lowest latency access to the
最低延迟
display.
接入显示屏的 API
It works identically on both our
它一样能工作在我们的
fixed frame rate and ProMotion
固定帧率以及 ProMotion
hardware, but once you opt in it
硬件上 一旦你选择它
starts working with much, much
它将以非常好的粒度
better granularity.
进行工作
The second of our Metal
我们的第二个
presentation APIs is present
Metal 展示 API
with minimum duration.
可以显示最短时间
So this one says, whenever this
图像无论何时
image lands on the glass, keep
登陆眼镜
it there for a certain fixed
它将能使它固定在眼镜里
amount of time.
一段时间
So if my image lands on the
如果我的图片在眼镜里
glass here, it's going to stay
被放了在这里
for 33 milliseconds.
它将持续 33 微秒
And if my start time shifts so
如果我的开始时间变化了
does the end time.
结束时间也会相应变化
This is the API you'd use if you
如果你想要
want perfect consistency in
帧与帧之间
frame rate from frame to frame.
有完美的连续性的帧率 这就是你要的 API
This is particularly useful in
它在每秒 30 帧的时候
30 frames per seconds -- on 60
在每秒 60 帧的显示屏上
rate per seconds displays,
尤其有效
although it's also sometimes
虽然它有时候在
useful on ProMotion as well.
ProMotion 上也很有效
But our third presentation
而我们第三个展示的
varying is the most interesting
变化是
by far.
目前最有趣的
It's present at a specific time
它会在特定的时间显示
and it does exactly what it
它做的事情和它听起来
sounds like.
一样
If the GPU's done well before
如果 GPU 在设定时间之前
the designated time, the display
就早早完成了 显示器会
will wait.
等候
If the GPU runs over your
如果 GPU 超过了你的
deadline the display will pick
时间限制 显示器会
it up at the very next available
在下一个可用的点将它
point afterwards.
取出
This is the key API to use if
如果你想创建一个完全
you want to build fully custom
定制的动画和时间循环
animation and timing loops.
这就是关键的 API
This API to present and time,
这个 API 的展示和时间
combined with ProMotion display
和 ProMotion 显示器相结合
basically lets you leave behind
基本上可以让你抛弃
the concept of a fixed frame
固定帧率的概念
rate entirely and render your
在用户将要
content exactly for the time the
看到内容的时候
user is going to see it.
再进行渲染
If you want to keep your Metal
如果你想要你的 Metal 视图
view perfectly in synch with
和其他正在系统里发生的东西
something else happening on the
完全同步
system, such as audio, or if you
例如音频 或者你想要
want to basically provide the
为所有的外观提供
appearance of zero latency at
零延时
all and be able to forward
然后在你的用户
project your animation for
将要看到内容的时候
exactly when the user's going to
再推进对象
see your content this is what
这是能让你实现这些
lets you do that.
的工具
Now of course the trick is
当然在这里的技巧
implementing that project next
是在下一个显示时间
display time.
执行对象
That's your function.
这就是你的功能
To make that work you do need
为了实现它 你需要一些
some feedback from the system to
来自系统的反馈
help you determine what your
来帮助你抉择
actual performance is.
你真正执行的是什么
And so we've added that as well.
现在我们也把它加上了
So a Metal drawable object is a
所以 Metal 可绘制对象
transient object that tracks the
是一个暂时的对象
lifetime of one image you've
它可以在显示系统里
rendered all the way through the
追踪一个被你渲染的图像
display system.
的一生
It can now be queried for the
现在它可以在特定的
specific time that frame lands
图像显示在眼镜上时被查询到
on the glass and you can also
当这件事发生时
get a call back when that
你也可以获得一个
happens.
回调函数
So now you can know when your
所以现在你可以知道你的图片
image is landing on the glass,
什么时候会显示在眼镜上
when they're being removed, and
以及它们被移除的时间
you have the key signal to know
你有关键的信号 能够使你知道
when you are or are not making
什么时候你在获得
the designated timing that you
你预期中的时间
intended and are giving you the
什么时候你没有
signal to adjust for future
然后给你一个信号
frames.
以调整未来的帧
So that's the story of ProMotion
这就是 ProMotion 的故事
and what you need to do to make
你将在未来
use of it on the future -- on
在新的 iPad Pro 上
these new iPad Pros.
使用它
It's incredibly easy to get more
在应用中几乎没有代码改变
consistent and higher frame
的情况下
rates with almost no code
要想获得更多的连续性和
changing at all in most
更高的帧率是
applications.
非常容易的
From there it gives you a menu
从这里开始 它将给你一个选项菜单
of options to decide what
让你选择哪一个
display time model is going to
显示时间模型会
best benefit your particular
对你的 app
app.
产生更多好处
A really, really fast paced
一个非常非常快的
Twitch arcade game or something
Twitch 电子游戏或者
tracking touch or pencil input
需要对触摸和铅笔输入进行追踪的应用
probably wants to go for 120
可能需要达到
frames per second.
每秒 120 帧
A really high end rendering
一个非常高端的渲染标题
title might want to stick with
可能需要保持
30 or 60 frames per second or
每秒 30 帧到 60 帧
somewhere in between and just
或者这之间的一个数
enjoy the consistency benefits.
以享受稳定连续的优势
And applications that want to
一些想要
really take control of their
完全掌控它们的
timing loop have entirely new
时间循环的应用在这里
capabilities here as well.
有全新的功能
But regardless of what your app
无论你的 app 是什么
actually is, ProMotion gives you
ProMotion 给予你这个
this powerful new tool to
强大的新工具
support its specific animation
去支持它特定的
needs.
动画需求
So that's ProMotion.
这就是 ProMotion
So moving on, I have a different
接下来 我有一个完全不同的
display topic to talk about and
显示话题要谈一谈
that is a feature we're calling
那就是我们称为直接显示的
Direct 2 Display.
功能
So the story of what happens
所以在你的 GPU
after your GPU finishes
完成渲染你的
rendering your content and the
内容和显示之后
display is actually a little bit
发生的事情会变的
more complicated.
复杂一些
And then your image can take two
然后你的图像有两条
paths to the display; GPU
可以通往显示屏的路径
composition and direct to
由 GPU 组合
display.
然后直接放到显示屏上显示
The first of those is a -- your
它们中的第一个是
typical user interface scenario
你的经典用户界面场景
where I've got a collection of
我会在这里获得一系列的
views or layers or windows and
视图 层级 和窗口
the like and at this point the
然后这个时候
system is going to take all of
系统会将
these and composite them
它们统统取出
together.
然后将它们组合起来
It's going to scale any content
它将缩放任何内容的比例
to fit the display.
以适应显示屏
It's going to perform
它将展示
color/space conversion.
色彩和空间的变换
It's going to perform -- apply
它将进行
any core image filters or
任何核心的图像过滤或者
blending and it's going to
混合 然后它将
produce the one, final combined
产生一个用户看到的
image that the user sees.
最终的组合图像
This is really, really critical
这对于功能完善的
abstraction for full-featured
用户界面
user interfaces.
是非常关键的抽象
But it's also all done on the
但是它也全部是在 GPU 上完成
GPU and it takes some time and
而且它会消耗一些时间和
memory there.
内存
And if we're basically building,
如果我们创建一个
you know a full-screen
全屏幕的应用
application, you know it's a
这对它来说
little bit overkill for that.
就有点过度了
And so that's where direct
这就是直接显示模式
display mode comes in.
介入的时候了
If none of these operations are
如果这些操作都没有被要求
actually required, we can point
我们可以
the display hardware directly at
直接让显示器硬件指向你
the memory you just rendered to
刚刚渲染过的内存
and so without any middleman at
而不需要任何
all.
中间人
So how do you enable this?
我们怎么做到的呢
It turns out there is no single
事实证明 其实没有一个
turn it on API for direct to
API 能够直接
display.
指向显示器
This mode is really an omission
这个模式实际上是
of anything that requires the
任何需要 GPU 组合器
GPU compositer to intervene.
介入的遗漏
When the compositer takes a look
当组合器看到你的
at the set-up of your scene and
场景设置 然后发现
says there's nothing it needs to
这里没有需要它做的
do here it will just step out of
这时候
the way.
它将离开
So how can you set up your scene
所以 你应该怎样设置你的场景
to get the compositer to step
以使合成器
out of the way?
直接离开
So this is pretty
其实这是
straightforward, an intuitive
非常直观的感受
feel of, does my content need
我的内容是否需要任何
any kind of nontrurial
非重要过程
[phonetic] processing is a
语音处理就是一个
pretty good intuitive start.
非常直观的开始
But more specifically you do
但更具体来说
want your layer to be opaque.
你希望你的层级是不透明的
I don't want to be blending over
我不希望它与任何东西
anything.
混合
We don't want to apply anything
我们不想运用任何
that requires that core
需要核心动画或者
animation or the window server
窗口服务器
modify our pixels.
来修改我们的像素
We don't want to put on rounded
我们不想在我们的视图里
corners in our view or masking
或者遮蔽或者过滤器这一类的东西
or filters or the like.
放置圆角控件
We do want to be full-screen.
我们想创建一个全屏幕
If your content does not
如果你的内容
actually match the aspect ratio
不完全符合
of the display it is okay to put
屏幕的纵横比例
a full-screen, opaque, black
你可以用全屏的 不透明的 黑色的
background layer to sort of give
背景层来给予
a black bar kind of effect.
黑色菜单栏一类的效果
But in the end we want to
但是最终我们还是希望
basically obscure everything.
能模糊所有的东西
We do want to pick render
我们希望选择一个
resolutions that match the
能匹配本来面板的
native panel.
渲染分辨率
So this is actually a little bit
这是有一点技巧性的
tricky because all of our --
因为我们所有的
both on macOS and iOS we ship
在 macOS 和 iOS 上搭载的
hardware that has a virtual
硬件都是有
desktop modes or resolution
虚拟桌面模式或者分辨率模式
modes that are larger than the
它们都比真实的物理面板
actual physical panel.
要大
And the last thing we want to do
我们想做的最后一件事
is spend time rendering too many
是花时间去渲染很多的
pixels only to have to spend
像素 其实只要
time on the GPU to scale it all
在 GPU 上花时间然后再把时间
back down again.
缩减回来就行了
And finally, you want to pick a
最后 你想选择
color, space, and pixel format
颜色 空间 像素帧
that the display hardware is
那些显示硬件
happy to read from directly.
会很高兴的直接读取的内容
And so this one, there's any
在这里
infinite number of combinations
这里有无限组合数
here so I want to help out by
所以在这里我想
giving you a little bit of a
给你们一个
white list of some particularly
关于一些特殊
common and efficient
和高效组合数
combinations.
的白名单
So right on the top is our good
在最上方是我们的
old friend; SRGB8888.
老朋友 SRGB8888
This is pretty much the
这基本上是绝大多数应用
universal pixel format that most
通用的像素格式
applications use and all
也是所有硬件都
hardware is happy to read.
乐于读取的
And so for most people that's
对于大多数人来说
all they need.
这就是他们需要的全部了
But we've been shipping wide
但是我们已经在
color gamut P3 displays on both
macOS 和 iOS 硬件上都
our macOS and iOS hardware and
搭载了广色域的 P3 显示器
if your application does want to
如果你的应用
start making use of this ability
希望开始运用这个功能
to represent more colors, you
来显示更多的颜色
need to pay a bit more
你需要
attention.
注意一下这里
In both the -- the concepts are
在这里 iOS 和 macOS 两者的概念
the same between iOS and macOS,
是一样的
although the details differ a
虽然在细节上
little bit.
有所不同
In both cases we do want to
在这两者中 我们都希望
render to attend the pixel
渲染加入像素格式
format, but note that if you
但是请注意 如果你
render P3 content onto a P3
在 P3 显示器上
display that's fine, but if you
渲染 P3 的内容 那没有问题
render P3 content onto an SRGB
但如果你渲染了 P3 内容
display the system -- the GP
然后在 SRGB 的系统里去显示
compositer might have to get
那么 GPU 合成器可能会
involved to crush the color
参与进来并将色域
space back down to fit the
压缩以适应
display.
显示器
And so this is -- P3 is not
所以 P3
something you want to do
不是你在任何时间
universally, all the time.
都想要做的
you do want to take a look at
你最好看一看
the current display and make
当下的显示器是什么
this a conditional thing.
然后在现有条件下工作
So finally, for completeness I'm
最后  为了完整性
also going to list RGBA float
我也要列出 RGBA float 16
16, which is sort of the
它基本上是
universal, wide gamut, high
普遍适应的 宽色域
dynamic range pixel format.
高动态范围的像素格式
Although, in -- I do -- it's
虽然
also necessary for MacOS's
这对 macOS 的
extended data range feature.
扩展数据范围功能也很必要
Although it is worth noting that
值得注意的是
it does require GPU compositing
它也确实需要在所有情况下
in all cases.
运行组成 GPU 组合
So I mentioned, you do want to
所以就像我提到的
be a little bit conditional if
如果你编写了一个
you write an application that's
广色域识别的应用
wide color aware.
你确实需要考虑条件
Fortunately, both UIKit and
幸运的是 UIKit 和
AppKit provide really convenient
AppKit 都提供了非常
APIs to check that.
简便的 API 检查方式
So the last step is, how do you
所以 最后一步是 你怎么知道
know if you're actually on the
你是否在
directed display path?
定向显示路径上
So this is a screen shot of our
这张截屏显示的是
Metal system trace tool and
Metal 系统的
instruments.
追踪工具
And Metal system trace is pretty
Metal 系统追踪是
much a developer tool that will
一个能给你实时的
give you a live timeline of the
CPU 和 GPU 显示器时间轴的
CPU and the GPU in the display.
开发工具
Pretty much a real-world version
这基本上是
of the diagrams I've been
我之前给大家展示过的
showing you in this
图像的
presentation.
真实版本
So in this case, I want to
所以在这里
highlight my three frames that
我要将渲染过的三个帧
I've rendered.
高亮显示出来
The color-time intervals are my
这个有颜色的时间间隔是我
own application's rendering.
自己的应用渲染
And the gray time intervals are
这个灰色的间隔是
some other processes in the GPU.
GPU 里的其他过程
I can get more details down at
我能在窗口底部
the bottom of the window or I
获得更多细节
can see it's coming from
我也能从背板 D 上看到它
backboard D, our iOS composition
这是 iOS 合成
process.
的过程
So this is the case where my
这是我的应用
application is going down the
到 GPU 合成路径上的
GPU compositing path.
例子
Going back and revisiting some
回到之前 重新访问
of our best practices can remove
一些我们的最佳实践例子
that from the picture and now I
会将它们从图片上移除
can rerun my Metal system trace
现在我可以返还我的 Metal 系统追踪
and see that I have a timeline
我有一个时间轴
where, you know I've got the GPU
可以通过它看到我已经
completely and entirely to
完全的
myself.
拥有了 GPU
So that's it for direct to
这就是
display.
直接显示
Our system compositors can make
我们的系统合成器可以
a lot of magic happen behind the
在屏幕后制造很多魔法
scenes to make full-featured
以使全功能的
user interfaces possible, but
用户界面成为可能
that can come at a performance
但是这会产生性能消耗
cost because they use the GPU to
因为要使用 GPU 来
do it.
做到它
By being a little bit aware of
通过了解
what you're asking the
你在要求
compositer to do, or more
合成器做什么 或者
importantly by not asking what
更重要的是 别问
you're not asking the compositer
你没让合成器做的事
to do, it can get out of the way
它就能不使用 GPU
without using the GPU, returning
从而离开
some of that time to you.
并返还给你一些时间
Direct to display is supported
iOS 和 Tos 一直
on iOS and Tos and always has
支持直接显示
been and its support is new to
这对 macOS High Sierra 的
macOS High Sierra for Metal
Metal 应用来说是
applications.
全新的
So with that I want to touch on
所以 讲到它 我想提到今天的
our last topic of the day and
最后一个话题和
that's everything else.
一些其他的东西
There's a lot more that we've
我们为 Metal 2
added to the core frameworks and
在核心结构和设计语言上
sheeting language for Metal 2.
做了很多添加
And so I'm not going to dive
所以现在我不打算
deep into any of these things,
深入的讲这些东西
but I do want to give you a
但是我想先给你们一个
survey.
调查
So right off the bat we've added
我们很快的添加了
some new APIs to be able to
新的 API 使它能够
query how much GPU memory's
质询 GPU
being allocated for each buffer,
为每个缓存器
for each texture, for each Heap.
每个纹理 每个堆分配了多少内存
This actually takes into account
这将屏幕后
things that just generally
发生的事情
happen behind the scenes, like
考虑在了其中
alignment and various padding.
例如对齐和多种填充
So this can give you a more
这能为你究竟
accurate view of how much GPU
使用了多少 GPU 内存
memory you're actually using.
提供一个更准确的视角
We also have a roll-up query on
我们在 Metal 设备上也有
the Metal device, which is the
一个折叠查询
entire GPU memory usage for your
它是你整个处理过程的
entire process.
GPU 内存使用情况
And this is particularly notable
这是尤其显著的
because that also counts all of
因为它包括了
the memory that the driver needs
所有对你不可见的
to allocate that's not otherwise
由驱动程序分配的内存
visible to you; things like
类似于
memory to put shader code in or
放置着色器代码的内存
command buffers or anything
命令缓存器或者其他类似的
else.
东西
So this can give you where
这能让你知道你
you're at relative -- you know
在哪里是关联的
everything all in compared to
你知道所有东西的
your memory usage target.
内存使用目标
We have a couple compute
我们有几个
oriented additions.
面向计算机的添加
The first of those is that we've
我们第一个添加的
added a set of shading language
是一系列着色语言功能
functions to help -- to allow
以帮助
you to transfer data directly
你能够在 SIMD 组的
between threads in a SIMD group.
线程之间转换
If you're not familiar; GPU
如果你还不熟悉的话
hardware typically gains an
GPU 硬件获得一个
individual vertex fragment and
单个顶点片段
compute shader thread into SIMD
然后计算着色器线程进入
groups and executes them
SIMD 组 然后一起执行它们
together for greater efficiency.
以获得更好的效率
This are also called wayfrencer
它们也被称为
[phonetic] warps.
wayfrencer warp
Within a group these threads do
在一个组里 这些线程
have some ability to directly
有能力不加载或者
communicate without having to
储存内存
load and store through memory.
直接进行对话
They can read values directly
它们可以从一个
out of one thread's register and
线程的寄存器读取值然后
write them to another thread's
将它们写入另一个
register.
线程寄存器
And that's what these new
这些就是
standard library functions
新的标准库
allow.
允许的内容
So in this case broadcast means
这里的广播意味着
I can read a data directly --
我能直接从线程零的寄存器
read a field directly out of
读取数据
thread zero's registers and
直接读取数据域
write it directly into the
然后直接将它写进
registers of 16 other threads
正好同属于这一个组里的
that happen to be part of this
其他 16 个线程的
group.
寄存器
Our second compute addition is
我们第二个增加
to give you more flexibility in
让你根据你的线程组大小
how big your thread groups are.
获得更多灵活性
So for example if I have a pixel
例如 如果我有一个
bird here that I want to run
像素鸟 我想要运行
some pretty classic image
一些漂亮的经典图像的
processing kernel over, but then
处理内核
I've written my compute kernel
但是我已经将计算内核
such that I'm using four by four
所有地方都写成了 4 乘 4 的
thread groups everywhere.
线程组
Well, this leads to some
好吧 这导致了一些问题
problems because I've got -- if
因为
my image is not a nice multiple
如果我的图片不是我的线程组的
of my thread group size I've got
数倍
a bunch of stray threads on the
我会产生
side.
很多偏离线程
I mean this means that I've got
我想这意味着
to dive into those and say when
我需要对它进行深入了解
I actually write my code.
然后当我真的要编写代码的时候
I have to be defensive.
我必须要谨慎
Am I out of bounds?
我越界了吗
I have to handle it in some
我需要用特殊的方法
special way.
来处理它
It's doable but annoying.
这是可行的 但是令人恼火
It also means that we're just
这基本是意味着
wasting GPU cycles.
我们只是在浪费 GPU 循环
So non-uniform thread group
所以非一致线程组的大小
sizes, unless you declare what
除非你声明
dimensions you want to run your
在不放大线程组大小的情况下
kernel over, without being
你想要在哪种维度上
multiple thread group sizes.
进行你的核心运行
So the hard working, smaller
所以那些困难的工作
thread groups along the edges of
在我的网格边缘的较小的
my grid, in order to say -- in
线程组上
order to just shave off that
为了去掉
unnecessary work it both
不必要的工作
improves GPU performance and
它不仅提升了 GPU 的性能
just makes your kernels easier
而且还让你的核心变得更
to write.
容易编写
We've added support for a view
我们已经加入了
port arrays.
对视图端口队列的支持
You can now configure up to 16
现在你可以设置最多 16 个
simultaneous view ports and your
同步的视图端口
vertex shader can select, per
而你的顶点着色器可以选择
triangle, which view port that
每个三角想向哪一个视图端口
triangle gets presented into.
进行呈现
I'm not going to go further into
在这里我就不多讲了
this because it will be
因为明天的 Metal 2
discussed in detail tomorrow in
VR 会议将会讲到关于它的
the VR with Metal 2 session.
细节
It is particularly valuable for
这对左右眼的
efficiently rendering to the
有效渲染是非常
left and right eyes.
有价值的
We've added the ability to
我们已经加入了一项能力
choose where in each pixel your
它可以选择在每个像素上
multi-sample locations are
你的多个实例位置
supported.
在哪里被支持
This lets you do a few
这让你能做一些
interesting things including
有趣的事情 包括
maybe toggling your sample
每隔一帧切换
positions every other frame and
你的实例位置
giving you some new -- you know
并给你一些新的 你知道
valuable input into some
将一些有价值的输入加入到
temporal anti-aliasing
一些随机采样抗锯齿
algorithms.
算法里
In the vein of trying to keep --
为了努力保持
of working to bring our
使我们的平台能跟得上时代
platforms up to date to have
让他们在任何时候
them have the same feature set
都有相同的功能设置
wherever possible, we've brought
我们用了
resource Heaps, shipped last
我们在去年的 iOS 10
year in iOS 10 to macOS High
以及今年的 macOS High Sierra 上
Sierra this year.
搭载的资源堆
So I'm going to actually do a
在这里我要
little bit of a refresher on
做一下刷新
this because good use of your
因为好好使用
Heaps is really important to
堆
getting the most out of argument
对于很好的利用参数缓存器
buffers.
很重要
So Heaps are of course where I
堆使我们能
can allocate a big slab of
预先分配很多
memory up front rather than
内存  而不是
going to the kernel to -- I want
去到内核然后说
memory for texture a, and I want
我要纹理 a 的内存
memory for texture b and so
我要纹理 b 的内存
forth.
等等
I can go to the kernel and get
我可以去内核
memory right up front and of
预先分配内存
course put textures -- you know
增减纹理和缓存器的同时
add and remove textures and
不需要
buffers to -- without having to
回到
go back to the system.
系统中去
This has a few advantages.
这样做有一些好处
It means that I can bind
这意味着我能
everything in that Heap much
在这个堆中更高效的
more efficiently.
混合所有东西
There's much less software
这样会减少很多
overhead.
软件开销
It means that we can oftentimes
这意味着我们可以
pack that memory a little bit
经常将内存
closer together.
压缩的更紧密一些
We can save some padding and
我们可以减少一些边距
alignment, save you a little bit
和队列 为你省下
of memory.
一些内存
It means when we delete memory
这意味着当我们删除内存时
we don't give memory back to the
我们不会将内存
system.
返还给系统
That could be good or bad.
这是好事也是坏事
It means when we allocate new
这意味着当我们分配
memory -- when we allocate a new
新内存时
texture it means we don't have
当我们分配新的纹理时
to go back to the system and get
我们不用回到系统
new memory.
去索取新的内存
It also means that you can
这也意味着你可以
choose to alias these textures
选择对这些纹理
with each other.
进行重命名
If I have -- you typically
如果我有
render targets or intermediate
渲染目标 或者
render targets between different
在渲染图形的不同通道上对
passes in my render graph.
渲染图像进行调整
It means that if I have two
这意味着
different intermediates that
如果我有两个中间结构
just don't have to exist at the
它们不用同时出现
same point in time I can alias
我可以
them over each other and I can
为他们设置相互命名
save tons of memory like this.
我可以像这样
So that's it for a quick survey
省下很多内存
of Heaps.
这是一个对堆的快速调查
We've added linear textures from
我们在 iOS 到 macOS 里都
iOS to macOS.
添加了线性纹理
Linear textures allows you to
线性纹理能使你直接从
create a texture directly from a
Metal 缓存器里创建纹理
Metal buffer without any copies
而不用做任何的
at all.
复制工作
We've extended our function
我们也扩展了
constant feature a little bit.
我们功能的稳定性
A quick refresher, function
一个快速的刷新
constants allow you to
稳定功能让你
specialize by codes.
用代码进行特殊化
When you've done all your front
当你在线下做完了
end compilation offline you can
你的前端编译
then tweak and customize your
你能够在产生最终的
uber shader bi-code a little bit
机器代码之前就
before actual generating final
对超着色器 bi-code 进行一些
machine code.
调整和自定义
If you have a classic uber
如果你有经典的
shader this can save you the
超着色器 它能为你省下
cost of having to re-run the
为每个单独序列
compiler front end for every
都配置一个前端编译器的
single permutation.
开销
So we've made this a bit more
所以我们已经将它变得
flexible and added a few more
更灵活 也添加了一些
cases where you can use these
能特殊化参数的
specialized arguments.
功能
We've added some extra vertex
我们也增加了一些额外的
array formats.
顶点数组格式
We had some missing one and two
我们遗漏了一个或两个
component vertex formats.
组件顶点格式
And we've also added BGRA vertex
我们还增加了 BGRA 顶点
formats.
格式
We've brought iOS surface
我们从 macOS 到 iOS 都
texture support from macOS to
有 iOS 的
iOS.
表面纹理支持
And we've also brought dual
我们也在 iOS 上加入了
sourced blending to iOS as well,
双源混合
also particularly useful in some
这在很多延迟渲染场景下
deferred shading scenarios.
尤其有用
So that's -- brings us to the
这就是我关于 Metal 2
end of introducing Metal 2.
介绍的最后内容
My colleague, Michal, started
我的同事 Michal
with giving you a little bit of
在开始的时候
an overview of the overall scope
向你们介绍了 Metal 2 的
of Metal 2.
总体范围
From VR to external GPUs, to
从 VR 到外部 GPU
machine learning, and to new
到机器学习
developer tools and performance
到新的研发者工具和
analysis.
性能分析
Of that, the pieces that we
我们今天介绍的
really covered today are our
这些内容
next big push toward reducing
极大地的推动了
CPU overhead using argument
通过使用参数缓存器
buffers.
来减少 CPU 开销
Argument buffers also unlock the
参数缓存器也解锁了
ability for the GPU to start
GPU 的能力
taking a little bit of its own
使它在配置
destiny when it comes to
着色器参数时
configuring shader arguments,
掌握一些它自己的命运
which is one less reason to take
这也少了一个
back to the CPU.
让它回到 CPU 去的理由
Raster Order Groups let us start
光栅顺序组让我们
using the rasterizer for things
在基本的东西以外
beyond basic in order blending.
使用光栅器来进行混合
We can now start taking
我们现在可以开始
advantage of the latest hardware
利用最新的硬件能力去做到
capabilities to do, you know,
你知道的
vox slice triangle meshes or set
vox slice 三角网络或者
transparency blending either in
设置有序或独立的
order or independent.
透明混合
They're both -- it makes them
它们都是
both possible.
这让它们都变成可能
For the new iPad Pros, ProMotion
对于新的 iPad Pros ProMotion
gives you very fine grained
能让你对于
control over exactly how your
动画如何呈现给用户
animations are presented to the
拥有一个细粒度程度的控制
user, giving you the ability to
让你有能力既
get both peak frame rates and
得到峰顶的帧率
the lowest possible latency.
又得到最少的延迟
Direct to display provides you a
直接显示通过发现我们的
path to reclaim a little bit of
合成器代表你做了什么
GPU performance from the system
来为你提供
by being aware of what our
重新声明 GPU 执行路径的
compositors do on your behalf.
能力
So you'll be able to find the
你可以在
video and the slides for this
WWDC2017 的网站上看到
session on the WWDC2017 website.
今天会议的幻灯片和视频
We have three other sessions on
我们今年还有
Metal 2 this year.
其他三个关于 Metal 2 的会议
In particular, tomorrow
特别要提到的是
afternoon we're going to have a
明天下午
session dedicated to VR and
我们的会议将集中讨论
Metal 2.
VR 和 Metal 2
This is going to go deep into
会议将
what your application needs to
深入讲解你的应用
do and a conceptual overview of
需要做什么 以及如何
how to do VR rendering, dive
做 VR 渲染的概念性简介
into specifically how to do VR
深入讲解
with the combination of Metal 2
如何用 Metal 2 和 Steam VR toolkit
and the Steam VR toolkit.
的组合来做 VR
It's also going to go into using
它也将通过外部的
Metal with external GPU
GPU 硬件
hardware.
来使用 Metal
On Thursday we have a
在周四 我们将有
doubleheader starting with Metal
连续两场会议 以 Metal 2
2 optimization and debugging.
的优化和故障排查开始
This is going to go into what's
会议将介绍
new in our developer and
新的研发项目
performance tools and all the
和性能工具
new workflows that enables to
以及所有的
help you build the best
帮助你创建尽可能完美应用
applications possible.
的工作流
And it's going to be followed up
接下去的会议
right after that with using
将会介绍
Metal 2 for compute.
使用 Metal 2 进行计算
And that's going to really have
这将是
a big focus this year on using
今年的重大关注点
the GPU for machine learning
使用 GPU 来做机器学习
applications.
应用
We've added a whole lot this
我们今年做了非常多的
year and we want to show you
添加 我们也希望
everything we've done.
向大家展示我们做了哪些事
I want to point you to a couple
我想给大家介绍
of last year's WWDC sessions.
几个去年的 WWDC 会议
The first, What's New in Metal
第一个是  Metal 的新鲜事
Part One is where we did a deep
第一部分 我们深入的讲解了
dive on resource Heaps.
资源堆
And instead if you're looking to
如果你想要得到
get the best performance out of
参数缓存器的最好性能
argument buffers, argument
参数缓存器和堆
buffers and Heaps were built to
是密不可分的
go together and so I highly
所以我非常鼓励
encourage you to go check out
大家去看看视频
the video and really -- and, you
真的 你可以
know basically plan your
通过一起使用这两项
application around both of those
来计划
together.
制作你的应用
They cover that in a lot more
那个视频里比今天的会议
detail than we did here today.
多讲了很多细节
Second, if the conversation
第二 如果你对
about direct to display and wide
直接显示和广色域
gamut and wide color interested
有兴趣
you we have a whole session that
我们在去年有
really goes deep into the
一次会议全程
concepts and the specifics
都在深入探讨
behind that, we also talked
它背后的概念
about last year.
和特殊性
With that I think we'll wrap it
在这里 我们今天的会议
up.
到此结束
I thank you for all attending
感谢大家的到来
and I hope you enjoy the
希望大家
remainder of your week.
享受本周剩下的几天
So thank you.
谢谢大家
[ Applause ]
[ 掌声 ]